School of the Museum of Fine Arts Records UA133
Tufts Archival Research Center
- 2019 accessions, 1875 -- 2016; UA133.014; Museum of Fine Arts, Boston. School; 129.88 Linear Feet 90 record cartons; 54 bound items; 6 document boxes; 5 oversize boxes.
  - Clippings, photos, film, video oversize, 1960 -- 1997; UA133.001696 (Box 488)
  - Dean's office records, 1970 -- 1995; UA133.001697 (Box 489)
  - Clippings, photos, film, video, 1960 -- 1997; UA133.001812 (Box 490)
    - Museum School Film 1968-1970, circa 1976; UA133.001813; 1 Audiovisual Object(s); 1 Digital Object(s) 1 VHS tape; 152 Megabytes (Box 490)
  - Press clippings, public relations, photos, 1980 -- 1995; UA133.001698 (Box 491)
    This box also contains student records, student rosters, and class lists, 1961-1983.
  - Press clippings, public relations, photos, 1980 -- 1995; UA133.001699 (Box 492)
  - Clippings, photos, 1940 -- 1990; UA133.001700 (Box 493)
  - Clippings, photos, 1940 -- 1990; UA133.001701 (Box 494)
  - Exhibitions, awards, gifts to the library, circa 1940s -- 1995; UA133.001702 (Box 495)
    Records containing information related to student education and staff and faculty employment are closed for 75 years from the date of creation. This file may require review before it is available for use. Please contact TARC for further details.
  - Exhibitions, awards, gifts to the library, circa 1940s -- 1995; UA133.001703 (Box 496)
  - Capital campaign/adminstrative records, 1980 -- 1999; UA133.001704 (Box 497)
  - Capital campaign/adminstrative records, 1980 -- 1999; UA133.001705 (Box 498)
  - Capital campaign/adminstrative records, 1980 -- 1999; UA133.001706 (Box 499)
  - Capital campaign/adminstrative records, 1980 -- 1999; UA133.001707 (Box 500)
  - Capital campaign/adminstrative records, 1980 -- 1999; UA133.001708 (Box 501)
  - Capital campaign/adminstrative records, 1980 -- 1999; UA133.001709 (Box 502)
  - Board of Governors/Development records, 1970 -- 1996; UA133.001710 (Box 504)
  - Board of Governors/Development records, 1970 -- 1996; UA133.001711 (Box 505)
  - Board of Governors/Development records, 1970 -- 1996; UA133.001712 (Box 506)
  - Board of Governors/Development records, 1970 -- 1996; UA133.001713 (Box 507)
  - Memorial, Michael Silver, 2004 -- 2005; UA133.001714 (Box 508)
  - Memorial, Michael Silver, 2004 -- 2005; UA133.001715 (Box 509)
  - Deborah Dluhy, Dean's office records, 1992 -- 2006; UA133.001716 (Box 510)
  - Deborah Dluhy, Dean's office records, 1992 -- 2006; UA133.001717 (Box 511)
  - Board of Governors records, 1992 -- 2006; UA133.001718 (Box 512)
  - Board of Governors records, 1992 -- 2006; UA133.001719 (Box 513)
  - Board of Governors records, 1992 -- 2006; UA133.001720 (Box 514)
  - Board of Governors records, 1992 -- 2006; UA133.001721 (Box 515)
  - SMFA Self-Study for National Association of Schools of Art and Design, Dean Dluhy records, 2004 -- 2010; UA133.001722 (Box 516)
  - SMFA Self-Study for National Association of Schools of Art and Design, Dean Dluhy records, 2004 -- 2010; UA133.001723 (Box 517)
  - Faculty and travelling scholar biographies, 1960 -- 2000; UA133.001724 (Box 518)
  - Faculty and travelling scholar biographies, 1960 -- 2000; UA133.001725 (Box 519)
  - SMFA's Massachusetts Department of Higher Education degree granting application and approval, 2012 -- 2013; UA133.001726 (Box 520)
  - Finance, development, public relations, planning, circa 1950s -- 2009; UA133.001727 (Box 521)
  - Course/program catalogs, 1893 -- 1991; UA133.001728 (Box 522)
    Lacks catalogs for 1940-1950.
  - Course/program catalogs, circa 1990s -- 2002; UA133.001729 (Box 523)
  - Course/program catalogs, 2001 -- 2019; UA133.001730 (Box 524)
  - Oversize documents, 1900 -- 2015; UA133.001731 (Box 525)
    This box includes course catalogs, 1975-1977 and 2000-2002; a 1979 staff picnic scrapbook; long range planning materials circa 1990s; an agreement with Tufts, 1956; and building planning materials, 1970s-1980s.
  - Clippings and information regarding SMFA faculty, graduates, exhibitions, and events, 1990 -- 2005; UA133.001732 (Box 526)
  - World War II Civil Defense, Dean Russell Smith and administrative records, 1942 -- 1968; UA133.001733 (Box 527)
  - Miscellaneous catalogs/minutes/reports, 1977 -- 1988; UA133.001734 (Box 529)
  - Day Without Art, 1883 framed photo, 1989; UA133.001735 (Box 530)
  - Clippings/library information, art tools, 1997 -- 2004; UA133.001736 (Box 531)
  - Dean's office transfer 2016, 1984 -- 2016; UA133.001737 (Box 532)
  - Dean's office transfer 2016, 1984 -- 2016; UA133.001738 (Box 533)
  - Dean's office transfer 2016, 1984 -- 2016; UA133.001739 (Box 534)
  - Dean's office transfer 2016, 1984 -- 2016; UA133.001740 (Box 535)
  - Dean's office transfer 2016, 1984 -- 2016; UA133.001741 (Box 537)
  - Dean's office transfer 2016, 1984 -- 2016; UA133.001742 (Box 538)
  - Dean's office transfer 2016, 1984 -- 2016; UA133.001743 (Box 539)
  - Dean's office transfer 2016, 1984 -- 2016; UA133.001744 (Box 540)
  - Dean's office transfer 2016, 1984 -- 2016; UA133.001745 (Box 541)
  - Dean's office transfer 2016, 1984 -- 2016; UA133.001746 (Box 543)
  - Dean's office transfer 2016, 1984 -- 2016; UA133.001747 (Box 544)
  - Scrapbooks, 1878 -- circa 1900; UA133.001748 (Box 545)
  - Scrapbooks, 1885 -- circa 1905; UA133.001749 (Box 546)
  - Scrapbooks, 1905 -- 1909; UA133.001750 (Box 547)
  - Scrapbooks, 1909 -- 1911; UA133.001751 (Box 548)
  - Scrapbooks, 1911 -- 1913; UA133.001752 (Box 549)
  - Scrapbooks, November 1913 -- May 1914; UA133.001753 (Box 550)
  - Scrapbooks, July 1914 -- October 1915; UA133.001754 (Box 551)
  - Scrapbooks, October 1915 -- January 1917; UA133.001755 (Box 552)
  - Scrapbooks, December 1916 -- circa June 1918; UA133.001756 (Box 553)
  - Scrapbooks, November 1918 -- circa November 1919; UA133.001757 (Box 554)
  - Scrapbooks, 1920 -- 1921; UA133.001758 (Box 555)
  - Scrapbooks, 1921 -- 1923; UA133.001759 (Box 556)
  - Scrapbooks, December 1923 -- April 1926; UA133.001760 (Box 557)
  - Scrapbooks, April 1926 -- March 1930; UA133.001761 (Box 558)
  - Scrapbooks, 1930 -- 1932; UA133.001762 (Box 559)
  - Scrapbooks, 1932 -- 1936; UA133.001763 (Box 560)
  - Scrapbooks, March 1935 -- October 1940; UA133.001764 (Box 561)
  - Scrapbooks, October 1940 -- April 1962; UA133.001765 (Box 562)
  - Scrapbooks, 1950 -- 1964; UA133.001766 (Box 563)
  - Scrapbooks, 1964 -- 1968; UA133.001767 (Box 606)
  - General scrapbooks, 1977; UA133.001768 (Box 564)
  - General scrapbooks, 1978 -- 1979; UA133.001769 (Box 565)
  - General scrapbooks, 1980 -- 1981; UA133.001770 (Box 566)
  - General scrapbooks, 1981; UA133.001771 (Box 567)
  - General scrapbooks, 1982; UA133.001772 (Box 568)
  - General scrapbooks, 1983; UA133.001773 (Box 569)
  - General scrapbooks, 1984; UA133.001774 (Box 570)
  - General scrapbooks, 1984 -- 1985; UA133.001775 (Box 571)
  - General scrapbooks, 1985; UA133.001776 (Box 572)
  - General scrapbooks, 1985 -- 1986; UA133.001777 (Box 573)
  - General scrapbooks, 1986; UA133.001778 (Box 574)
  - General scrapbooks, 1987; UA133.001779 (Box 575)
  - General scrapbooks, 1989 -- 1990; UA133.001780 (Box 576)
  - Grand Tour, Mary Hallowell Loud scrapbook, 1905; UA133.001781 (Box 577)
  - Grand Tour scrapbook, No. 1, 1904 -- 1905; UA133.001782 (Box 578)
  - Grand Tour scrapbook, No. 2, 1909 -- 1911; UA133.001783 (Box 579)
  - Grand Tour scrapbook, No. 3, 1911; UA133.001784 (Box 580)
  - Grand Tour scrapbook, No. 4, 1905; UA133.001785 (Box 581)
  - Grand Tour scrapbook, No. 5, 1906; UA133.001786 (Box 584)
  - Grand Tour scrapbook, No. 6, 1907; UA133.001787 (Box 582)
  - Grand Tour scrapbook, No. 7, 1904; UA133.001788 (Box 583)
  - Grand Tour scrapbook, No. 8, 1905 -- 1906; UA133.001789 (Box 585)
  - Grand Tour scrapbook, No. 9, 1913; UA133.001790 (Box 586)
  - Grand Tour scrapbook, No. 10, 1906; UA133.001791 (Box 587)
  - Grand Tour scrapbook, No. 11, 1913; UA133.001792 (Box 588)
  - Administrative records: Office of Dean William Bagnall, 1967 -- 1975; UA133.001793 (Box 589)
  - Faculty meetings, 1967 -- 1973; UA133.001794 (Box 590)
  - Administrative records, 1971 -- 1979; UA133.001795 (Box 591)
  - Administrative records, 1971 -- 1979; UA133.001796 (Box 592)
  - Dean's office, 1987 -- 2001; UA133.001797 (Box 593)
  - Dean's office, 1987 -- 2001; UA133.001798 (Box 594)
  - Permanent Committee, Alumni Association bylaws, SMFA annual reports, Secretary's records, 1875 -- 1895; UA133.001799 (Box 595)
  - Permanent Committee, 1890 -- 1902; UA133.001800 (Box 596)
  - SMFA School Council, 1902 -- 1907; UA133.001801 (Box 597)
  - SMFA School Council, 1907 -- 1913; UA133.001802 (Box 598)
  - SMFA School Council, 1913 -- 1924; UA133.001803 (Box 599)
  - SMFA School Council, 1924 -- 1936; UA133.001804 (Box 600)
  - SMFA School Council, 1936 -- 1954; UA133.001805 (Box 601)
  - Scrapbook, SMFA exhibitions, 1927 -- 1953; UA133.001806 (Box 602)
  - Scrapbook, personal family, 1910 -- 1923; UA133.001807 (Box 603)
  - Secretary's records, 1888 -- 1902; UA133.001808 (Box 604)
  - Clippings, photos, film, video, 1960 -- 1997; UA133.001809 (Box 605)
- Web crawls, 2017 -- 2020; UA133.001810; 1 Web sites
  This series contains the web crawl for the School of the Museum of Fine Arts' website. The website is crawled on a montly basis.
  Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
  Archived websites can be viewed online using the Internet Archive's Wayback Machine.
  Other Finding Aids
  To see all of websites crawled as part of the Tufts University web collection, please visit the Archive-It collection page.
  - SMFA at Tufts | School of the Museum of Fine Arts, 2017 -- 2020; UA133.001811; 1 Web sites
    Crawled monthly.
    Related Materials
    For captures of this website prior to August 2017, see https://web.archive.org/web/*/http://www.smfa.edu/
- 2021 accessions, UA133.001814
  Transferred by School of the Museum of Fine Arts student Luna Doherty-Ryoke, 2021, accession UA-2022-003.
  This series contains zines created by School of Museum of Fine Arts students for the course SMFA-0119 Flyers and Zines.
  - SMFA-0119 Flyers and Zines student work, 2021; UA133.001815 (Box Shared 145, Folder 8)
- 2023 accessions, 2017 -- 2022; UA133.001850; 0.25 Linear Feet 1 half letter size document box
  This series contains SMFA Senior Thesis Program exhibition catalogs.
  Transferred by Kendall Reiss, SMFA Professor of the Practice, 2022, accession UA-2023-028.
  - SMFA Senior Thesis Program exhibition catalogs, 2017 -- 2022; UA133.001851; 0.25 Linear Feet 1 half letter size document box (Box 637)
    SMFA Senior Thesis Program exhibition catalogs for the years 2017-2022.